Alejandro Ruiz Huertas

Date of birth: 01/05/1999 | Gender: Male | Phone number: (+34) 619275507 (Mobile) | Email address:

ruizarh99@gmail.com | Website: alejandroruizhuertas.github.io | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-ruiz-6212a5194/ Address: Spain (Home)

About me:

I am Alejandro Ruiz, Computer Engineer with 1.5 years of experience. I have worked in the development of IoT platforms, also with knowledge in API REST, MQTT, web, Linux containers, AWS, agile methodologies and ESP32, among others. Currently, I am studying a Master in Computer Engineering at the University of Malaga, specializing in Cybersecurity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/08/2021 - CURRENT Tomelloso, Spain

FULL STACK DEVELOPER 426 CODE

Full Stack Developer in the Development department, currently working in the Smart City SmartTelia platform, carrying out design and development of software components integrated in the platform itself, data migration to non-relational databases, critical backend refactorings, among others.

02/02/2021 - 04/08/2021 Tomelloso, Spain

INTERNSHIP COMUNITELIA TELECOMUNICACIONES

Internship in the R&D department, in the Smart City SmartTelia platform.

13/11/2020 - 21/07/2021 Ciudad Real, Spain

CORPORATE TREASURER CIREBITS

Member of the board of directors, in charge of the company's economic flow, bank accounts, budget planning.

17/10/2019 - 21/07/2021 Ciudad Real, Spain

PARTNER CIREBITS

Different jobs for the junior company Cirebits: Design and creation of web pages, assistant and presentation of different technological elements of Cirebits, promotion hostess of the Escuela Superior de Informática - UCLM, Scratch teacher for children between 10-12 years old, among others.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2021 - CURRENT Málaga, Spain

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING Universidad de Málaga

Address Málaga, Spain | Website https://www.uma.es/master-en-ingenieria-informatica |

Field of study Cybersecurity

08/09/2017 - 21/07/2021 Ciudad Real, Spain

DEGREE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING Escuela Superior de Informática - UCLM

Address Paseo de la Universidad, 4. Edificio Fermín Caballero, Ciudad Real, Spain

Field of study Information and Communication Technologies

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **SPANISH**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	B2	C1	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Soft Skills

Communication | Adaptability | Motivation | Responsability | Creativity | Teamwork | Problem-solving

Programming Languages

Java | Python | R | JavaScript | Typescript

Databases

RDS | MongoDB | MySQL | MariaDB

Web

HTML5 | CSS | REST | MERN STACK

Network Security

IPS/IDS (Snort, Suricata) | OpenVPN | Firewalls

Internet of Things

MQTT | Smart City

Others

Linux | Git | CI/CD | AWS | Docker

Interests

Machine Learning | Artificial Inteligence | Computer Vision | Web Pentesting